MD. Maruf Hossain

Full Stack Web Developer

maruf14@cse.pstu.ac.bd • +8801724783655 • Mirpur 10, Dhaka, Bangladesh • marufalaslam.github.io

https://github.com/marufalaslam • https://www.linkedin.com/in/webdevmaruff

Career Objective

Self Motivated team player with four years of experience seeking a position as a web developer with Next generation Web Development Technologies, where I can apply my knowledge of web development with my leadership abilities to meet client needs exceed their expectations.

Professional Experience

Associate Frontend Developer

CoreXLab Limited

12.2022 – present Dhaka, Bangladesh

React.js, JSX, Tailwind, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Component Libraries, Node.js, Express.js, Git, Github, Asana,

Freelance Frontend Developer

Fiverr.com

10.2020 - present

Barishal, Bangladesh

HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Tailwind, PHP, MySQL, WordPress, Elementor, PSD to HTML, Figma to HTML, XD to HTML.

Trainer - Responsive web design and Development

Learning & Earning Development Project, ICT Ministry, Bangladesh

Basic Computer, Internet Browsing, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, jQuery, PSD to

HTML, XD to HTML, Figma to HTML, WordPress, WooCommerce.

02.2020 – 05.2022 Dinajpur, Bangladesh

Skills

Comfortable (C, C++, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ES6, Bootstrap, Tailwind, React.js, React Router DOM, DaisyUi, Material UI, FlowByte, jQuery, CSS Media Query),

Familiar (Redux, Node.js, MongoDB, Express.js, PostgreSQL, React Native),

Tools (VS Code, Git, CLI, Browsers, Chrome Developers tool)

Projects

E-Trade | Full Stack Product Resale Website

11.2022 - 12.2022

- MERN Stack project where users can sign in/register and buy/sell their used products.
- Firebase Authentication and JWT Authorization.
- Important Tools: React.js, Node-Express, MongoDB, Middlewares, React Router DOM, Tailwind, DaisyUl, NPM Packages, Git, Stripe Payment Method

Live Link: https://e-trade-a12.web.app/ ☑

Client Repository: https://github.com/MarufAlAslam/mern-product-resale-client 🗹 Server Repository: https://github.com/MarufAlAslam/mern-product-resale-server 🗹

Picman | Full Stack Service Review Based Website

11.2022 - 11.2022

• MERN Stack Project where users can register/sign in and see/provide reviews on services available on the website. also, they can add services if they want.

- MongoDB Databases, Firebase Authentication, Firebase Hosting, JWT Authorization.
- Important Tools: React.js, Node-Express, MongoDB, Middlewares, React Router DOM, Tailwind, DaisyUl, JWT, NPM Packages, Git

Live Link: https://picman-a11.web.app/ ☑

Client Repository: https://github.com/MarufAlAslam/mern-pickman-client

Brain Exercise || React Firebase Authentication Website

10.2022 - 10.2022

- React App with Firebase Authentication (email-password, GitHub, google)
- An online course-based website where users can sign in/register and see details of any courses.
- Important Tools: React.js, Firebase Authentication, Firebase Hosting, React Router DOM, Private Route, Tailwind, DaisyUI, Git.

Live Link: https://brain-exercise-60233.web.app/ ☑

Education

B.Sc. Engineering in Computer Science & Engineering.

Patuakhali Science & Technology University

01.2017 – 04.2022 Patuakhali, Bangladesh

Languages

Bengali (Native), English (Fluent), Hindi (Conversational)

References

MD. Mahbubur Rahman, Assistant Professor,
Dept. of CSIT, Patuakhali Science & Technology
University
mahbub.cse.buet@gmail.com, +88015564499873

Interests

- To become a MERN Developer
- To Develop interactive web apps with next generation technologies
- To become a Traveller

Declaration

I hereby consciously ascertain that, all the particulars mentioned above are true. I myself will be liable of any misinformation mentioned herewith.

MD. Maruf Hossain

Marint